<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Violence on Juan TORRES MUNGUÍA, PhD</title>
    <link>http://localhost:4321/categories/violence/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Violence on Juan TORRES MUNGUÍA, PhD</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4321/categories/violence/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A model-based boosting approach to risk factors for physical intimate partner violence against women and girls in Mexico</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/publications/risk_factor_physical_violence_mexico_computational_soc_sci_2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/publications/risk_factor_physical_violence_mexico_computational_soc_sci_2024/</guid>
      <description>Abstract The goal of this study was to identify and describe the extent to which a comprehensive set of risk factors from the ecological model are associated with physical intimate partner violence (IPV) victimization in Mexico. To achieve this goal, a structured additive probit model is applied to a dataset of 35,000 observations and 42 theoretical correlates from 10 data sources. Due to the model&#39;s high dimensionality, the boosting algorithm is used for estimating and simultaneously performing variable selection and model choice.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An analysis of the risk factors for intimate partner sexual violence against women and girls in Mexico</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/publications/risk_factor_sexual_violence_mexico_2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/publications/risk_factor_sexual_violence_mexico_2024/</guid>
      <description>Abstract The goal of this study is to identify the extent to which a set of risk factors from the ecological model are associated with intimate partner sexual violence victimisation in Mexico.&#xD;To achieve this goal, a structured additive probit model is applied to a dataset of 35,004 observations and 42 correlates.&#xD;Findings indicate that age at sexual initiation, women’s sexual and professional autonomy, and social connectedness are associated with their victimisation risks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Determinants of Emotional Intimate Partner Violence against Women and Girls with Children in Mexican Households: An Ecological Framework</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/publications/risk_factors_emotional_violence_mexico_2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/publications/risk_factors_emotional_violence_mexico_2022/</guid>
      <description>Abstract The purpose of this paper is to identify the risk factors for emotional intimate partner violence (IPV) against women and girls with children in Mexico from an ecological perspective. To that end, we generate a dataset with 35,004 observations and 42 covariates, to which we apply an additive probit model estimated with a boosting algorithm to overcome high-dimensionality and simultaneously perform variable selection and model choice. The dataset integrates 10 information sources, allowing us to properly characterize the four levels of the ecological approach, which is the first contribution of this paper.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Violent Crime in Latin American Cities</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/publications/violent_crime_latam_iadb_2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/publications/violent_crime_latam_iadb_2016/</guid>
      <description>Abstract In the last two decades, Latin America has been describes as an unsafe and violent region. Nonetheless, such picture is mostly based on homicide rates. Even though homicide is considered the best recorded crime, it does not provide full account of other forms of violent crime. Moreover, a great deal of research on crime throughout the region tends to be descriptive and anecdotal. Misunderstanding the causes of crime and disregarding evidence might induce policy makers to implement ineffective strategies, particularly at the local level.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
